{"id":"2017_4","name":"Romans2017_4","memoryVerse":"“For God does not show favoritism.” – Romans 2:11","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2017_4_1","questionText":"1. What was meaningful to you in the lecture?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_4_2","questionText":"2. What help did you receive from the notes?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Romans 3:1-4.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:1-4"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_4_3a","questionText":"3. a. What expectations might the Jews in Paul’s day have had about their spiritual advantages? (See also Romans 2:6-29.) What expectations of God do you have concerning any spiritual advantages you may have?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"2:6-29"}]},{"id":"2017_4_3b","questionText":"3. b. Why was it an advantage for the Jews that God entrusted them with His very words, and how is God’s Word, the Bible, a great advantage for you?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_4_4","questionText":"4. Try to connect the promises God made to the Jews with Romans 3:3-4. (Some of the promises are found in Genesis 12:1-7; Deuteronomy 30:15-20; Jeremiah 31:35-37. There are several interpretations.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:3-4"},{"book":"Genesis","verse":"12:1-7"},{"book":"Deuteronomy","verse":"30:15-20"},{"book":"Jeremiah","verse":"31:35-37"}]},{"id":"2017_4_5","questionText":"5. Ultimately, who is responsible for a person’s sin and unbelief? Why? (See Psalm 51:1-6; James 1:13-14.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"51:1-6"},{"book":"James","verse":"1:13-14"}]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Romans 3:5-8.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:5-8"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_4_6","questionText":"6.  What “human argument” did Paul expose as wrong, and why was God’s wrath justified?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_4_7","questionText":"7. What should be the believer’s attitude toward sin, and how does your attitude toward sin compare with your  actions? (Use any Bible passages you wish to support your answer.) ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Romans 3:9-18.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:9-18"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_4_8a","questionText":"8. a. From these verses, what are the promised effects of sin, and how have you seen these effects in your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_4_8b","questionText":"8. b. What words in verse 13-14 reveal how seriously God views our speech? What warning do you receive about your words, and what specifically will you ask God to help you change? (See also James 3:5-10.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"James","verse":"3:5-10"}]},{"id":"2017_4_9","questionText":"9. According to verse 18, what sin appears to underlie the sins in verses 13-17, and how does this passage show this root sin is true of people in both Old and New Testament times?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_4_10","questionText":"10.  What does it look like to fear (have a reverent awe for) God? ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Romans 3:19-20.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:19-20"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_4_11","questionText":"11. What does Paul conclude in verses 19-20?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_4_12a","questionText":"12. a. What does it mean to have every mouth silenced and the whole world accountable to God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_4_12b","questionText":"12. b. How has the study of Romans helped you to identify, confess and repent of your sin?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Romans 3:1-20.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:1-20"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_4_13","questionText":"13.  What have you learned about God in this week’s study? How may your group pray for you as you make this truth a part of your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}